<resources>
    <string name="app_name">HealthyPaws</string>
    <string name="training">Training</string>
    <string name="events">Events</string>
    <string name="diet">Diet</string>
    <string name="dog_profile">Profile</string>
    <string name="start_screen_background">start screen background</string>
    <string name="healthy_paws">Healthy Paws</string>
    <string name="healthy_paws_description">Train your dog, track his diet and develop your cooperation!</string>
    <string name="get_started_button">Get started</string>
    <string name="dismiss_button">Dismiss</string>
    <string name="search">Search</string>
    <string name="forward">forward</string>
    <string name="exercises">Exercises</string>
    <string name="games">Games</string>
    <string name="clicker">Clicker</string>
    <string name="suggested_exercises">Suggested exercises</string>
    <string name="show_all_button">Show all</string>
    <string name="dog_image">Dog image</string>
    <string name="commands_i_know">Known commands</string>
    <string name="go_back">go back</string>
    <string name="whistle_image">whistle image</string>
    <string name="change_clicker_sound">Change whistle sound</string>
    <string name="dog_sit_image">dog sit image</string>
    <string name="difficulty">Difficulty</string>
    <string name="dog_exercise_image">dog exercise image</string>
    <string name="add_button">Add button</string>
    <string name="add_diet">Add diet</string>
    <string name="backspace">Backspace</string>
    <string name="add_diet_description">Add meal description</string>
    <string name="go_forward">Go forward</string>
    <string name="add_diet_name">Add meal name</string>
    <string name="diet_name">Diet name</string>
    <string name="diet_description">Diet description</string>
    <string name="go_to_ex_description">Go to exercise description</string>
    <string name="add_to_known">Add to known</string>
    <string name="menu">menu</string>
    <string name="remove_dog">Remove dog</string>
    <string name="edit_dog">Edit dog</string>
    <string name="add_dog">Add dog</string>
    <string name="change_dog">Change dog</string>
    <string name="dog_profile_image">Image of a dog</string>
    <string name="default_image_path">file:///android_asset/images/dog.png</string>
    <string name="goBack">Go back button</string>
    <string name="dog_name">Name:</string>
    <string name="dog_breed">Breed:</string>
    <string name="dog_date_of_birth">Date of birth:</string>
    <string name="enterImageMsg">Tap image to add/replace image</string>
    <string name="cannot_create_image_file">Cannot create image file</string>
    <string name="cannotTakePicture">Cannot take picture</string>
    <string name="action_view_dogs">uk.ac.aber.dcs.cs31620.healthypaws.action.VIEW_DOGS</string>
    <string name="dogs_uri">http://healthypaws.cs31620.dcs.aber.ac.uk/dogs</string>
    <string name="ok">Ok</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="pickDate">Pick a date</string>
    <string name="difficulty_easy">Easy</string>
    <string name="difficulty_medium">Medium</string>
    <string name="difficulty_hard">Hard</string>
    <string name="event_name">Event name:</string>
    <string name="event_date">Date:</string>
    <string name="pickTime">Pick a time:</string>
    <string name="event_time">Time:</string>
    <string name="go_to_diets">Meals</string>
    <string name="articles">Articles</string>
    <string name="go_to_list_of_events">List of events</string>
    <string name="article1Title">Understanding Dog Nutrition: What to Feed and When</string>
    <string name="article2Title">Dangerous Foods for Dogs: What They Must Avoid</string>
    <string name="article1_image">Article 1 image</string>
    <string name="article2_image">Article 2 image</string>
    <string name="article3_image">Article 3 image</string>
    <string name="article3Title">Feeding Your Dog: Tips for a Healthy Diet</string>
    <string name="article1_paragraph1">For the health and wellbeing of our beloved friends, proper diet is crucial. Understanding the fundamentals of dog nutrition is essential for responsible pet owners who want to make sure their canine friends are getting the proper nutrients at the right time.</string>
    <string name="article1_paragraph2">Commercial dog food and homemade dog food are the two primary choices when it comes to dog food. Commercial dog food comes in a variety of formats, including dry kibble, wet canned food, and freeze-dried or dehydrated food. It is specially prepared to fulfil the unique nutritional needs of dogs. On the other hand, making meals for dogs at home using safe, nutritionally-balanced ingredients is known as homemade dog food.</string>
    <string name="article1_paragraph3">No matter what kind of food is selected, it\'s crucial to adhere to the feeding recommendations made by the manufacturer or a veterinarian. These recommendations often take the dog\'s age, weight, amount of exercise, and breed size into account. Adult dogs need a balanced diet to maintain their ideal bodily condition, while puppies need a diet that is high in protein and calories to support their growth and development. Senior dogs may require a modified diet, including less calories to avoid weight gain and joint supplements to support the health of their joints.</string>
    <string name="article1_paragraph4">"Timing of feedings is just as important as meal variety and quantity. Two meals a day are usually plenty for adult dogs, but pups may require three to four smaller meals to prevent hypoglycemia. To preserve a dog's digestive health and avoid obesity, it's critical to set and adhere to a feeding schedule. "</string>
    <string name="article1_paragraph5">To keep dogs hydrated, it\'s important to provide them frequent meals in addition to fresh water at all times. Numerous physiological functions in a dog\'s body, including as digestion, circulation, and temperature control, depend on water. Dehydration can cause a number of health problems, therefore it\'s crucial to frequently check and restock the water dish.</string>
    <string name="article1_paragraph6">"In conclusion, giving the appropriate food, according to feeding recommendations, setting a feeding schedule, and assuring constant access to fresh water are all part of knowing dog nutrition. Making a diet plan specific to a dog's needs may benefit from consultation with a veterinarian or a competent veterinary nutritionist. "</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph1">Dogs have a reputation for being opportunistic eaters and will frequently try to eat everything that is offered to them. But not all human meals are risk-free for dogs and can seriously jeopardise their health. We must be aware of foods that are poisonous or hazardous to dogs as responsible pet owners and refrain from giving them to our four-legged pets.</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph2">Dogs should generally avoid foods like chocolate, coffee, alcohol, onions, garlic, grapes, raisins, and avocados. These meals include ingredients that can be poisonous to dogs and result in a range of symptoms, including tremors, seizures, vomiting, diarrhea, stomach discomfort, and in severe cases, even death.</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph3">"Foods heavy in fat, including fried items and fatty meat cuts, can also be harmful to dogs. They may cause pancreatitis, a disorder that can cause vomiting, diarrhea, and excruciating abdominal pain when the pancreas is inflamed. It's also a major no-no to feed dogs with bones, especially cooked ones since they can shatter and lacerate or impede the digestive track. "</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph4">Dogs can develop allergies to some human foods. Dairy products, wheat, soy, and specific types of meat are among the foods that cause allergies in dogs. It\'s crucial to seek a veterinarian\'s advice if a dog displays symptoms of food allergies, such as scratching, skin rashes, gastrointestinal problems, or recurring ear infections.</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph5">"In general, it's advisable to give dogs a full and nutritionally balanced dog food and to refrain from giving them table scraps or human meals without first contacting a veterinarian. Make sure the treats or snacks you give your dog are produced particularly for dogs and don't include any unhealthy substances. "</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph6">If you accidentally eat something harmful, call your veterinarian right away. Treatment options might include inducing vomiting, giving activated charcoal, giving intravenous fluids, or doing additional supportive measures, depending on the kind and quantity of food consumed.</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph7">Additionally, it\'s crucial to exercise caution around any food sources that a dog might be able to get, such as trash, compost, or objects left on the floor. As scavengers, dogs are known to consume damaged or rotting food, which can result in serious gastrointestinal distress and other health problems.</string>
    <string name="article2_paragraph8">In conclusion, it is essential for dogs\' safety and wellbeing to be aware of foods that are poisonous or dangerous to them. The best course of action is to stick to a nutritionally full and balanced dog food and to refrain from giving them table scraps or human food without first seeing a veterinarian. It is possible to assist guarantee that our animal friends remain healthy and content by keeping poisonous items out of their reach and taking proactive measures to prevent accidental intake.</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph1">One of the most crucial facets of good pet keeping is providing your dog with a nutritious and balanced food. In terms of a dog\'s general health, energy levels, and lifespan, a balanced food is essential. Here are some suggestions to assist you in feeding your canine partner a nutritious diet.</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph2">"Select High-Quality Dog Food: Seek out dog food that has the Association of American Feed Control Officials' complete and balanced designation. (AAFCO). These meals include a well-balanced combination of protein, carbs, fats, vitamins, and minerals and are designed to suit the nutritional needs of dogs. Avoid feeding your dog any food that has an excessive amount of fillers or byproducts, artificial preservatives, colors, or flavours. "</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph3">"Age, size, and activity level of your dog should all be taken into account when determining your dog's dietary needs. The food requirements of puppies, adult dogs, and elderly dogs vary. Compared to small breed dogs, large breed dogs may need a different diet. While less active or older dogs may require a reduced calorie diet to avoid weight gain, highly active dogs may require more calories and protein. To choose the right kind and quantity of food for your dog, speak with your vet. "</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph4">"Pay Attention to Portion Sizes: Obesity is a prevalent health problem in dogs and can be caused by overfeeding. Avoid free-feeding by according to the feeding instructions supplied by the manufacturer or your veterinarian. (leaving food out all day for your dog to graze on). To guarantee precise portion sizes, use a measuring cup, and modify the amount of food given to your dog based on its weight, activity level, and overall health. "</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph5">"Feeding your dog table scraps or human food might throw off their balanced diet and cause obesity or nutritional imbalances. Avoid giving your dog food from the table and stick to a full and balanced dog meal instead. "</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph6">Fresh Water Should Always Be Available: Your dog should always have access to clean, fresh water. Dogs require water to be hydrated, promote general health, help in digestion, control body temperature, and more. To guarantee that your dog has access to fresh water throughout the day, regularly check and refill their water bowl.</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph7">Treats are a terrific way to praise your dog and strengthen your relationship with them, but they shouldn\'t constitute a large amount of their diet. Choose dog-specific snacks that are wholesome and nutrient-rich and refrain from overfeeding your pet. To avoid overeating and subsequent weight gain, treats should be offered in moderatio</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph8">"Keep an eye on your dog's health frequently: Pay close attention to your dog's overall health, energy level, coat quality, and body condition. To rule out any underlying medical conditions that could necessitate nutritional modifications, speak with your veterinarian if you detect any changes in your pet's appetite, weight, or behaviour. "</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph9">Only use supplements with a doctor\'s approval: While certain dogs could benefit from specific supplements, such as joint support or omega-3 fatty acids, it\'s crucial to speak with your vet before introducing any new supplements to your dog\'s diet. If required, your veterinarian can determine the unique needs of your dog and provide the proper nutrients.</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph10">Don\'t Feed Your Dog from the Table: It\'s crucial to have a regular feeding schedule and to refrain from giving your dog food at the table or letting them nag for it. As a result, they could develop unhealthy eating habits, have an unbalanced diet, and beg more frequently.</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph11">Avoid Feeding Your Dog Late at Night: It\'s typically advised to avoid feeding your dog just before bed and to feed them earlier in the evening. This might lessen the likelihood of digestive problems in dogs that may develop after eating, such as upset tummies or regurgitation.</string>
    <string name="article3_paragraph12">In conclusion, feeding your dog a nutritious, well-balanced food is crucial for their general health and wellbeing. Choose a high-quality dog food, take into account your dog\'s age, size, and level of activity, pay attention to portion sizes, refrain from giving your dog any table scraps, offer fresh water, be careful of rewards, periodically check on your dog\'s health, and talk to your veterinarian if you think your dog would benefit from any dietary changes or supplements. You can make sure that your pet is getting the nourishment they require for a healthy and happy life by paying attention to the advice in this article.</string>
    <string name="no_dogs">No dog\'s profile to be displayed</string>
    <string name="up_background">Up background</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="stepOne">Step 1</string>
    <string name="stepTwo">Step 2</string>
    <string name="stepThree">Step 3</string>
    <string name="calendar_icon">Calendar Icon</string>
    <string name="time_icon">Time icon</string>
    <string name="meal_icon">Meal icon</string>
    <string name="article1_title_part1">Understanding Dog Nutrition </string>
    <string name="article1_title_part2">What to Feed and When</string>
    <string name="article2_title_part1">Dangerous Foods for Dogs </string>
    <string name="article2_title_part2">What They Must Avoid</string>
    <string name="article3_title_part1">Feeding Your Dog </string>
    <string name="article3_title_part2">Tips for a Healthy Diet</string>
    <string name="remove">Remove</string>
    <string name="references">"References: "</string>
    <string name="article1_reference1">ASPCA. (n.d.). People Foods to Avoid Feeding Your Pets. Retrieved from https://www.aspca.org/pet-care/animal-poison-control/people-foods-avoid-feeding-your-pets</string>
    <string name="article2_reference1">Pet Poison Helpline. (n.d.). Top 10 Human Medications Poisonous to Pets. Retrieved from https://www.petpoisonhelpline.com/pet-owners/basics/top-10-human-medications-poisonous-to-pets/</string>
    <string name="article3_reference1">Veterinary Medical Association. (n.d.). Senior Dog Health FAQ. Retrieved from https://www.avma.org/resources/pet-owners/petcare/senior-pet-care-faq</string>
</resources>